CAREER PROFILE

I have 2+ years of experience as a software developer, and I have a solid understanding of the analysis, design, and creation of web-based applications. My areas of expertise include user interface (UI) web application development using the most recent web technologies as well as understanding and experience with a variety of web development frameworks. I have strong analytical, problem-solving, and presentation abilities.

EXPERIENCES

Software Engineer

July 2021 - Present

Thinkitive Technology Private Limited, Pune

I am working as a software engineer since **July 2021** in **Thinkitive Technology**, In this time I worked on analytical, problem-solving, and presentation abilities. I am also skilled in test-driven development, model-view-template (MVT), and object-oriented design (OOD).

- Skilled in software development, including the design, development, and analysis of web applications.
- Able to develop **Websites** and **APIs** using a variety of frameworks, including Django, Flask, FastAPI and React.is.
- OOD and MVT expertise, as well as strong analytical, presentational, and problem-solving abilities.
- Maintaining good coding standards required participation in code reviews, working on spec papers for system architecture, and doing static analysis.



I have worked on these below listed projects in my professional working time.

Coeur.ai (Client - Octoshrew, Sep - Dec 2021)

- This is a next generation SEO platform that is built to model google's content-based ranking algorithm using Deep Learning.
- Stack Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, postgreSQL, Redis, Celery, Docker, Stripe

Insights and Analytics (Client - Mitratech, Dec 2021 - March 2022)

- Insights Dashboard contains an arrangement of charts. Each chart represent a set of data related to the agreement itself such activity, progress status, type, and average time. Insights Dashboards offers to the manager user the possibility of filtering data on demand according to the given criteria.
- Stack Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ETL (Java and Spring Batch), Docker

EraCLM - ContractRoom (Client - Mitratech, March 2022 - December 2022)

- EraCLM automates the process end to end, ensures complete content digitization, and provides dynamic, rule-based routing among all parties in an agreement. Everything is managed via a single, centralized platform. It also helps you solve many negotiation and contracting issues by streamlining every step of the process and providing deep post-contract insights for better obligation management and process optimization.
- Upgrade this project and also upgrade data to the new code base for PostgresSQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch
- Stack Python, Django, Django Restframework, Django CMS, Django Channels, SAM (SSO), Jinja Templates, JavaScript (JQuery), PostgreSQL, MongoDB (DocumentDB), ElasticSearch, AWS Services S3 Bucket, RDS, DocumentDB, Elastic Cache

IntraConnects (Client - Thinkitive, January 2023 to March 2023)

- Unified API is built on top of our well researched data models schema & is a robust and battle tested application programming interface, which enables intraconnects platform to allow you access for a single resource (e.g. Patient, Appointment, ...etc.) against various different EHRs with a single endpoint.
- EHR Athen, Open Epic, Cerner, NextGen, open EMR
- Stack Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, Redis, Celery, PostgreSQL, Docker

eCareMD - CCM (Client - Thinkitive, March 2023 to Now)

- Chronic care management involves the supervision and educational efforts carried out by healthcare
 professionals to support patients with chronic diseases and health conditions, such as diabetes, high
 blood pressure, multiple sclerosis, and sleep apnea, in comprehending their condition and effectively
 managing it.
- Stack Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, Redis, Celery, PostgreSQL, Docker, Multi Tenant, 2FA

Vikash Kumar

Software Engineer

- ✓ vikash1998bscc@gmail.com
- **J** 7004 987 522
- in /in/vikash-kumar-a40860176/
- github.com/vikash8407

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Python Javascript

Frameworks

Django Django Rest Framework Flask

FastAPI React.js Vue.js

Databases

PostgreSQL MySQL MongoDB Elastisearch

Frontend Technologies

HTML5 CSS3 Bootstrap5 Material-UI

Development and Deployment Tools

Git Docker Docker Compose Nginx uWSGI

Gunicorn Kubernetes GitHub Actions

Tools and Environments

VS Code PyCharm Sublime Bracket

Ubuntu Windows

Design, Modeling and Methodologies

Monolithic Microservices Rest API Agile

EDUCATION

B.Tech (CSE)

SAM College of Engineering and Technology, Bhopal

Intermediate

DAVPG College, Siwan 2014 - 2016

Matriculation

D P H School Madhopur (Gopalganj) 2013 - 2014

CERTIFICATES

Problem Solving (HackeRank)
Rest API (HackeRank)
SQL (HackeRank)

ACHIEVEMENT

- ★ I achieved **Above and Beyond** position in Thinkitive Technology for 2022 year.
- ★ I achieved **5 stars** on HackerRank for Python
- ★ I achieved **5 stars** on HackerRank for SQL.